So you may have heard of Pacman. Has anybody heard of Pacman?
No, maybe a little bit, okay.
Pacman is a great game from the
eighties. It's a trademark of
Namco Bandai and we're going to be using
it throughout this course to illustrate points in
this educational setting. You can think
of Pacman as an agent.
So, here, you look at this board. That's the Pacman board. What are the percepts?
What do you have when you play Pacman? So essentially Pacman the agent is not the game,
it's not something that draws the walls. What is
it? It's the thing behind the joystick.
What's that?
It's you. So essentially you're the agent when you play a game of Pacman. You're deciding,
do I go up down left right, and so on, and
what is your sensation? So what is the--
for you it involves your eyes, but
basically you see the whole board.
You know where the dots are, you know where the enemies are, you know where the walls are. What actions can you take?
Well you can go up or down or left
or right, and so if we have an agent
which maps the state of the board to
up-down-left-right, the question is,
what goes here in the question mark that lets
it know when to eat a dot, when to run away
from a ghost, when to use the power
pellet. How are these decisions all made?
And you might think, I know, if the
dot's next to me I eat it and if the
ghost is within three squares of me,
run away. And if you try to write this down,
first of all you would end up with the
biggest mess of if-then statements
you've ever seen, and then it wouldn't work.
We will in our projects get a chance
to build agents for games like this, and
you'll see why that kind of thing doesn't work.
Alright, let's take a look at
an agent
for Pacman.
So here is an agent playing the game of Pacman. This is a CS 188
Pacman-like game
and I'll let you watch. As you watch I want you
to think about what kinds of
computation must be going on in this agent in order to be able to
exhibit this range of behavior.
So we're gonna figure out in the coming
classes how we'll be able
to give rise to behavior like that.